Allen Snow

Senior Software Engineer Manager

4352 E Mercer Way Mercer Island, WA 98040



Programming languages

C#	•••••
JavaScript	••••
TypeScript	•••••
Swift	••••
Objective C	•••
Java	••

Application development

Web	••••
iOS	••••
Windows / XAML	•••
Android	••
macOS	•••
Xamarin	••

Web development

HTML	•••••
JavaScript	•••••
CSS	••••
React	••••
Node.JS	•••
ASP.NET / MVC	•••
Angular	••

Database

SQL Server	•••
Core Data	••••
CloudKit / iCloud	••

Game development

Jnity 3D	••
Blender	••
Maya	•

Passionate software engineer manager with a wide range of experience over multiple platforms and technologies. Skilled in all facets of product development life cycle from requirements gathering, analysis and conceptual design through architecture, program management, implementation, and ongoing support.

EXPERIENCE

MICROSOFT - July 2007 to Present

Senior Software Engineer Manager

Microsoft Teams – Developer Experiences Manager

Enabling developers to extend and integrate with Teams using tools, services and samples. Manage team of developers providing guidance and mentorship. Collaborate with organizations across the company and externally.

Azure Active Directory

Developer for Azure authentication library for JavaScript and iOS. Azure web management portal to support developers with the tools and code samples.

Universal Store and Marketplaces

Development of tools and services to supply marketplace experiences for customers across multiple platforms such as the web, mobile, and Xbox.

Microsoft Band Wearable

Development of cross platform companion applications that support the Microsoft Band for iOS, Android, Windows Phone, and the web portal.

Bing – Apps powered by Bing

Common library development for mobile and desktop applications.

Corporate Home Page and Download Center

Microsoft's corporate home page and Microsoft download center.

Windows

Project manager and developer for the Windows build and tools team.

FEDERAL BUREAU OF INVESTIGATION - May 2005 to July 2007

Senior Software Engineer

Lead developer in the training division unit that used gaming technologies to train agents and employees on various topics. Roles included project management, database design/development, and developing SharePoint customizations.

SS&C ADVENT - March 1999 - May 2005

Senior Software Engineer

Lead developer for systems that consisted of secure data processing and distributed backend systems related to the financial industry.

EDUCATION

WESTERN MICHIGAN UNIVERSITY - Kalamazoo, Michigan

Bachelor of Science, April 1997

Major: Computer Science, Minor: Mathematics